Guide to the Williamson Family papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series III: Manuscripts and Documents
  - Second Reformed Church of New Brunswick Receipt for $50 to Nicholas Williamson for pew rental, 9 July 1872 (Box 3)
  - Williamson, Nicholas, 1845-1902 Medical memoranda, (5 items Notebook, 1 vol) (Box 3)
  - Novelty Rubber Company (New York City) Accounts -- Lists of shareholders, 2 items -- Minutes, 27 January 1872 -- Minutes, 24 October 1872 (Box 3)
  - Williamson, James R Wedding invitation (Box 3)
  - Williamson, Nicholas, 1845-1902 His bank check for $19.50, 13 July 1874 (Box 3)
  - Novelty Rubber Company (New York City) List of stockholders, 1 January 1874 (Box 3)
  - Novelty Rubber Company (New York City) Accounts. 1 January 1875 (2 items) -- Annual meeting: announcement & notes (3 items) (Box 3)
  - Gifford, George Legal bill for $200 (Box 3)
  - Williamson, Douwe Ditmars Memo re. his becoming manager (Box 3)
  - Williamson, Nicholas, 1845-1902 Bank check for $107.28 to Ebenezer W. Price -- Medical lecture on the eye, [20 April 1876] (Box 3)
  - Williamson, Nicholas, 1845-1902 His bank check for $398, 31 March 1877 (Box 3)
  - Williamson, Sarah Cook (Mrs Nicholas) Elm Wood Cemetery Association Receipt for her grave, 13 August 1878 (Box 3)
  - New-Brunswick Vocal Union Concert program, 17 June 1878 (Box 3)
    [(with envelope)]
  - The Royal Society of Edinburgh Admission ticket, 2 December 1878 (Box 3)
  - Rutgers College Certificate of his admission in 1862, 8 December 1878, (3 tickets) (Box 3)
  - University of Edinburgh 8 tickets of admission (Box 3)
  - Lawrie, Mrs Bill for Nicholas Williamson's board, 17 January 1879 (Box 3)
  - University of Edinburgh Eleven certificates & other items for Nicholas Williamson (Box 3)
  - 3 diplomas (Box MapCase 14/10/3)
  - Williamson, Clara A Gurley The poets' year a birthday register, London, 1877 (Box 3)
    [With family birthdays filled in, 1879]
  - Williamson, Nicholas & Clara Augusta Gurley Marriage certificate, 2 June 1881 -- Wedding invitations, 2 June 1881 -- Wedding presents - list (Box 3)
  - Novelty Rubber Company (New York City) Account, 1 January 1881 (Box 3)
  - Burlock, Agnes Maria Codwise, 1798-1886 Receipt for $1,000 (Box 3)
    [(signed by William H. Blood)]
  - Williamson, Nicholas, 1845-1902, and others Guaranteeing loan from The National Bank of New Jersey to the city of New Brunswick for interest on city bonds for the sum of $10,000, 20 April 1884 (Box 3)
  - Burlock, Agnes Maria Codwise, 1798-1886 Memo of her assets, 28 September 1885 (Box 3)
  - Cook, Robert A Deed of sale of a house and lot in New Brunswick NJ to Nicholas Williamson for $1, 29 August 1885, (p.d.s.) (Box 3)
    [(also signed by C.L. Hardenbergh as witness and notary and by C.M. Slack as clerk)]
  - Burlock, Agnes Maria Codwise, 1798-1886 List of her assets, 31 Dec 1886 -- Probate copy of her will, 10 June 1874 -- Appointment of Nicholas Williamson as Executor, 13 September 1886 (Box 3)
    [(signed by Benjamin F. Howell, Surrogate)]
  - Williamson, Nicholas, 1845-1902 Bill of sale for 10 shares of stock, 10 December 1887 (Box 3)
  - Burlock, Agnes Maria Codwise, 1798-1886 Final accounting of her estate, 31 March 1888 (Box 3)
  - Williamson, Nicholas, 1845-1902 Lecture on influenza -- 2 speeches on municipal affairs (Box 3)
  - Troy Female Seminary Resolution re. the Gurley family donation, 23 May 1893 (Box Oversize)
  - Holmes, Oliver Wendell, 1809-1894 Rules of good manners (Box 3)
  - Williamson, Nicholas, 1845-1902 Speech on municipal affairs (Box 3)
  - Williamson, Nicholas, 1845-1902 Notice of his election as Mayor of New Brunswick NJ, 21 April 1897 (Box 3)
  - Rutgers Preparatory School Certificate of Charles Gurley Williamson, 10 June 1898 (Box 3)
  - Williamson, Nicholas, 1845-1902 Biographical note, (1 page t.ms.) (Box 3)
  - Williamson, Nicholas, 1845-1902 Notice of his election as Mayor of New Brunswick NJ, 17 April 1897 (Box 3)
  - Second Reformed Dutch Church Sunday School of New Brunswick N.J. Certificate of Mary Williamson, January 1900 (Box 3)
  - Pan-American Exposition (Buffalo NY) Invitation to the Mayor of New Brunswick NJ, 20 May 1901 (Box 3)
  - Second Reformed Dutch Church Sunday School of New Brunswick N.J. Certificate of Charles Gurley Williamson, 1 January 1901 (Box MapCase 14/10/3)
  - Williamson, Nicholas, 1845-1902 Memorial tributes at his death, (3 items) (Box 3)
  - Franklin College School report for Charles G. Williamson, 1 February 1905 (Box 3)
  - Williamson, Julia Bulkeley Watercolor portrait with pencil sketches on the verso, ca. 1906 (Box 3)
  - Williamson, Ruth A Diary, (1 volume) (Box 3)
  - Knickerbacker Hall (Indianapolis IA) (Box 3)
  - Diploma of Williamson, Mary A.B., 3 June 1909 (Box MapCase 14/10/3)
  - Williamson, Mary AB Diary, (1 volume) (Box 3)
  - Williamson, Ruth A Accounts (Box 3)
  - "The Leon Bakst Costume Book ...", 1916 (Box 3)
  - [An essay on civic improvement], Read before the Indianapolis Woman's Club, February 2d 1917 (Box 3)
  - Williamson, Ruth A Bill for her DeSoto automobile, 24 January 1941 (Box 3)
- Series IV: Photographs
  - Abeel, David, 1804-1846 -- Beveridge, Mary M Gurley -- Beveridge, Ruth -- Blood family -- Bulkeley, Mrs -- Burlock, Agnes Maria Codwise (Mrs David), 1798-1886 -- Codwise family -- Cook family -- Gurley family -- Kelley, Helena Dignard -- Reilly, Augusta STo rer Williamson -- STo rer, Agnes Williamson, 1870-1961 -- Thompson, Ruth Thayer -- Williamson, Agnes -- Williamson, Caroline -- Williamson, Catherine Bulkeley (Mrs Douwe D), 1854-1917 -- (Box 4)
  - Williamson, Charles Gurley, 1894-1947 -- Williamson, Clara Augusta Gurley (Mrs Nicholas), 1849-1918 -- Williamson, Clara Augusta Gurley -- Williamson, David Abeel -- Williamson, Douwe Ditmars, 1789-1869 -- Williamson, Douwe Ditmars, 1851-1918 -- Williamson, George Rogers, 1823-1851 -- Williamson, Gretchen (Box 5)
  - Williamson, Helen Lorraine -- Williamson, John -- Williamson, John Proudfoot -- Williamson, Julia Bulkeley -- Williamson, Mary AB -- Williamson, Mary Ann Abeel (Mrs Douwe D), 1790-1864 -- Williamson, Mary Rebecca Burlock (Mrs Nicholas), 1819-1857 -- Williamson, Nicholas -- Williamson, Nicholas, 1811-1862 -- Williamson, Nicholas, 1845-1902 -- Williamson, Nicholas, b ca 1880 -- Williamson, Ruth A -- Williamson, Sarah Cook (Mrs Nicholas) (Box 6)
  - Album, 1896-1902 -- Groups -- Negatives -- Places -- Unidentified (Box 7)
- Series V: Printed Material
  - Printed material, 1819-1961 & [n.d.] (Box 8)
  - 1790 Book of Common Prayer of the Abeel family with genealogical notes (Box Flat Box 230)
  - 1792 Bible of the Abeel family with genealogical notes (Box Flat Box 231)
  - 1801 Bible of the Codwise family with genealogical notes (Box Flat Box 232)